# Sunghwan Kim

Website: sunghwan.me Email: ssshwan@add.re.kr / ssshwan.korea@gmail.com Mobile: +82-10-4305-1311

### **Research Interests**

My research interests lie in computer vision, especially efficient algorithms for visual perception. Currently, I an exploring efficient algorithms and model structures to leverage pre-trained foundation models in vision (e.g., SAM) as building blocks for a variety of perception tasks.

Keywords: Visual Perceptions, Domain Generalization, Knowledge Distillation

### **Education**

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

B.S. in Electrical Engineering and Mathematics (double major)

GPA: overall 3.61/4.00; major 3.66/4.00

**Korea Science Academy of KAIST** 

Mar 2014-Feb 2017

High school for gifted students in mathematics and science

### **Publications**

2. Texture Learning Domain Randomization for Domain Generalized Segmentation [paper] Sunghwan Kim, Dae-hwan Kim, and Hoseong Kim International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023

1. Data Gathering Trials for the Development of Military Imaging Systems [paper] Maria Niebla, Duncan L. Hickman, Eunjin Koh, Chanyong Lee, Hoseong Kim, Chaehyoen Lim, Sunghwan Kim SPIE Sensors+Imaging, 2023

#### **Patent**

1. Method and System for Detecting Target Using Time Series Images Chaehyeon Lim, Sunghwan Kim, Hoseong Kim, and Eunjin Koh KR Patent, 2023 (Reg. Num. 10-2023-0031087)

# **Work Experience**

### Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

First Lieutenant and Machine Learning Research Engineer

Jun 2021-Present Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Feb 2017-Feb 2021

Advisor: Steven E. Whang

- Selected as one of the exclusive 20 military officers in Korea who conduct military service as research engineer at the ADD, Korea's counterpart to U.S. DARPA.
- Object detection in infrared imagery: Developed real-time object detection algorithms for defense systems. Generated synthetic infrared imagery for training data and constructed the entire learning pipeline.
- Model acceleration on edge devices: Implemented network compression techniques such as knowledge distillation, network pruning, and model quantization to accelerate models on edge devices like NPU.
- Deep learning-based application software for UAVs: Developed application software that seamlessly integrates resource optimization by multi-threading, and I/O interfacing with flight control system.

**Bluepoint Partners** 

Aug 2020-Mar 2021 Seoul, Republic of Korea

Research Assistant

- Bluepoint Partners is an early stage venture capital firm targeting tech sector, such as AI and robotics.
- Supported investments in tech-based startups and conducted market research for these investments.

**Paple** 

Jun 2019-May 2020 Seoul, Republic of Korea

Co-founder and Software Engineer

- Paple is a software platform with a community feature that allowing the meta-review of AI papers.
- Developed the backend using Django and built the database system with MySQL.

Machine Learning Engineer

Dec 2017-Feb 2018 Seoul, Republic of Korea

- Neosapience is a Series B startup that operates deep learning-based audio and video synthesis technology and has launched an AI-powered virtual actor service.
- Conducted data processing for the development of a Korean text-to-speech system.

# **Research Experience**

# Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

Researcher in missile IR seeker team

Jun 2022-Present Daejeon, Republic of Korea

- **Domain generalization in object recognition**: Explored methods for training robust models that learn from synthetically generated source images and perform effectively on diverse real-world images.
- Foundation models for enhancing downstream tasks: Exploring methods to leverage pre-trained foundation models in vision (e.g., SAM) to improve the efficiency and efficacy of segmentation tasks.

### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Oct 2018-Apr 2019

Undergraduate researcher in Intelligent Network Architecture (INA) lab

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

• **Super-resolution on edge devices**: Implemented an algorithm that combines neural super resolution with traditional video codecs to enhance streaming quality on edge devices.

### Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Jun 2016-Aug 2016

Invited researcher in Center for Axion and Precision Physics Center

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

• Researched on the detection of axion using resonant frequency measurements in a cylindrical cavity.

# Honor

Korea Army Startup Challenge Gold Prize (\$3000)

Korea Student Aid Foundation (KOSAF) Scholarship (\$1500)

Korea National Scholarship of Science and Technology (\$10000)

KAIST scholarship (\$5000)

# **Community Involvement**

KAIST Freshman Coach Senior	Feb 2020-Feb 2021
Samsung Semicoductor Education Program and Scholarship	Jun 2019-Present
Research Officiers for National Defense (ROND) cadat	Dec 2018-May 2021
KAIST Electrical Engineering Department Student Council	Mar 2018-Feb 2019
KAIST Cyber Tutoring Program	Feb 2018-Jun 2018
KAIST Foreign Buddy Program	Sep 2017-Dec 2017
KAIST Automobile Maker Club	Mar 2017-Aug 2018

### **Selected Coursework**

**Electrical Engineering**: Deep Learning, Database and Bigdata System, Signal Processing, Computer Architecture, Operating System, Computer Network, Digital System, Electrical Circuits, Electromagnetics

**Mathematics**: Linear Algebra, Mathematical Analysis, Probability theory, Statistics, Convex optimization, Numerical Analysis, Discrete Mathematics, Mathematical Modeling, Differential Geometry, Modern Algebra

### **Skills**

**Programming Languages**: Python, C/C++, JavaScript, MATLAB

Frameworks & Tools: Pytorch, Tensorflow, NumPy, OpenCV, Docker, Git

### References

Dr. Steven E. Whang, Associate Professor at KAIST

Dr. Hoseong Kim, Senior Reseacher at ADD

Dr. Dae-hwan Kim, Senior Reseacher at ADD

Email: swhang@kaist.ac.kr
Email: hoseongkim@add.re.kr

Email: dhkim7@add.re.kr